Register of the Walter Clay Lowdermilk Papers, 1914-1968
Hoover Institution Archives
Walter Clay Lowdermilk Papers,
1914-1968
70049
Lowdermilk, Walter Clay, 1888-1974
14 manuscript boxes, 3 envelopes (6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, printed matter, and photographs, relating to land use and soil and water conservation, primarily in China and Japan.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
United States. Soil Conservation Service.; Agriculture--China.; Agriculture--Japan.; Soil conservation--China.; Soil conservation--Japan.; Water conservation--China.; Water conservation--Japan.; China.; Japan.; United States--Foreign relations.
Biographical Note
1888, July 1 Born, Liberty, North Carolina
1914 B.A., School of Geology, Oxford University
1914-1915 Served with the Commission for Relief in Belgium
1917-1919 Military service -Timber acquisition officer
1919-1922 Research officer in Region One of the United States Forest Service
1922 Master's Degree, Oxford University
1922-1927 Made five agricultural expeditions into Northwestern China
1933 Associate Chief of the Soil Conservation Service of the United States Department of Agriculture
1937 Chief of Research
1939-1947 Assistant Chief of the Soil Conservation Service
1944 Author, Palestine, Land of Promise
1974 Died
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1914-1952
  - General (Box 1)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1920-1968
  - China (Box 1)
    - Agriculture, land-use and farming
    - Agriculture, land-use and farming (Box 2)
    - Forestry
    - Forestry (Box 3)
    - Water erosion, soil and water conservation, rivers and flood control (Box 4-8)
    - Water erosion, soil and water conservation, rivers and flood control (Box 9)
  - Japan
    - Erosion, land-use, soil and water conservation, rivers, and flood control
    - Erosion, land-use, soil and water conservation, rivers, and flood control (Box 10)
    - Erosion, land-use, soil and water conservation, rivers, and flood control (Box 11)
    - Forestry
  - Pacific area land use
- WRITINGS, 1942-1968
  - "China Survey, 1942-43," typewritten manuscripts (Box 11)
  - "The Science or Mechanism of Peace," 1968
  - "A Past and Future Perspective of the Chino-Japanese Conflict"
  - "A Study of Paricutin Volcano, Mexico," 1950
  - "Survey of Land-Use in Europe and the Near East, 1938-39," studies by W. C. Lowdermilk (Box 12)
  - "Survey of Land-Use in Europe and the Near East, 1938-1939," studies by W. C. Lowdermilk (Box 13)
  - 22 works based on 2 volumes of W. C. Lowdermilk's memoirs
  - Miscellaneous works
  - Miscellaneous works (Box 14)
- MEMORABILIA
  - General (Box 14)